最重要的是陛下还活着
The most important thing is that His Majesty is alive.
他还活着是因为乌斯塔莎是白痴，而不是因为我们有能力
He is alive because the Ustasha are idiots, not because we are capable.
我们准备忘记你参与了
We're ready to forget your participation
这次失败的暗杀
in this failed assassination.
将军
Mr. General.
发生了一起谋杀案
There was a murder.
日尔诺夫是你的问题，尽你所能去解决它
Zhrnov is your concern, solve it however you can.
- U.H. - 无名英雄
- U.H. - Unknown hero.
- 我们知道他是谁 - 谁埋在那里？
- We know who he is. - Who is buried there?
一个孩子，他的家人被杀了
A child. His family was killed.
如果你是来拿离婚协议书的，那你可不是挑了个好时机
If you came for divorce papers, you didn't pick a very good time.
放下枪，这样我就不会为你的灵魂唱歌了！
Throw that shit so I don't sing for your soul now!
亚塔汗贫民窟实际上是这个城市的贫民窟
The Yataghan slum is really a slum of this city.
这个项目将使贝尔格莱德成为欧洲的一部分
And this project should make Belgrade a part of Europe.
- 克劳斯 - 下午好
- Klaus. - Good afternoon.
他将和你同时在贝尔格莱德
He will be in Belgrade at the same time as you.
这条信息不应落入坏人之手
At no cost should this message fall into the wrong hands.
恐怕我不认识伯爵
I'm afraid I don't know the count.
利奥波德 · 诺维奇
Leopold Nowicki.
我们认为殿下
You know, we think that Our Highness,
出于对你们国家的热爱，准备采取草率的行动
out of great love for your country, would be ready for hasty moves,
比如承认苏联主权
such as the recognition of the Soviet Union, for example.
跟我来
Follow me.
萨夫科维奇先生，一切都准备好了
Mr. Savkovich, everything is ready.
是你杀了尼古拉·巴雅克塔维奇吗？
Did you kill Nikola Baryaktarevich?
他被复活的人杀死了
He was killed by the one who returned.
我们即将进入新的一年
We are entering the new year soon.
什么酒，你这个婊子? ！
What drink, you bitch?!
新的幻觉
The new illusion.
谁在那儿？
Who's there?
诺维奇伯爵
Count Nowicki.
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
愿今年更快乐、更平静
May this year be happier and calmer.
如果可能的话
If that's possible.
不会的，不过没关系，干杯！
It's not, but that's fine. Cheers!
你戒酒多久了？
How long have you not been drinking?
差不多一年了
Almost a year.
快点，吃完它！
Come on, finish it already!
午饭去我那里吃，家人在等着我们
Lunch is waiting for us at my place, in Avala.
这个老东西刚刚戒酒
This old man has just stopped drinking,
现在这个小家伙开始酗酒
and now this little one has started drinking like crazy.
别逼逼，拿点水来
Leave me alone and bring some water.
你不会和博雅纳和好吧？
You won't reconcile with Boyana?
即使我想，她也不会
Even if I wanted to, she wouldn't.
我们不要再谈这个了，拜托
Let's not talk about it anymore, please.
好的
We won't.
去找别人吧
Start looking for someone else, pal.
你还太年轻，不能像我这样生活
You're too young to live like me.
你是指看守罪犯还有走私白兰地？
You mean guarding criminals and smuggling brandy?
我不走私白兰地，我自己酿的
I don't smuggle brandy. I make it.
甚至走私也比在警察局工作更恰当
Even smuggling would be fairer than working in the police.
还有安排赌博活动? 这也恰当吗？
And securing gambling sessions? That's fair, too?
差不多吧
Pretty much.
我们在互相侮辱吗？
Oh, we're insulting each other?
你先开始的
You started first.
所有人都出去! 快点! 快点! 出去！
Everyone out! Come on! Faster! Come on! Out!
你为什么把我的客人赶出去，混蛋? ！
Why are you throwing my guests out, asshole?!
去吧台待着! 你以为你是谁? ！
Go to the bar! Who do you think you are?!
看着门
Watch the door.
我一直在贝尔格莱德到处找你
I've been looking for you all over Belgrade.
我看得出来你用我的钱
And you're having fun, as I can see.
玩得很开心，对吗？
With my money, right?
我不知道你说的是什么钱
I don't know what kind of money you're talking about.
哦，你知道的
Oh, you know.
你打牌从我这里偷的钱
The money you stole from me playing cards.
是时候还钱了
It's time to return that money.
跟我没关系，孩子
I have nothing to do with it, kid.
我真的很想帮你，但是我不知道怎么帮你
I would really like to help you but I don't know how...
我表弟从姆拉代诺瓦茨来过除夕夜了，你也看到了
My cousin from Mladenovac came for the New Year's Eve, as you can see.
表弟? 从姆拉代诺瓦茨来的？
Cousin? From Mladenovac, huh?
那你回姆拉代诺瓦茨吧，表弟！
Let's go back to Mladenovac, cousin!
再见
Goodbye.
听着..
Listen...
别再叫我孩子了
Stop calling me "kid".
不然要你好看，你个混蛋！
So I don't kick your ass, you motherfucker!
米伦... 别乱来
Milun... don't mess with that.
我会的，我想做什么就做什么
Oh, I will. I'll do everything I want.
你想偷我的东西? ！
You want to steal from me, huh?!
- 米伦! - 闭嘴！
- Milun! - Shut up!
别打断我，而你... 起来，把钱找出来！
I'm talking now. And you... Get up and find the money!
- 米伦! - 搞什么? ！
- Milun! - What the fuck?!
别动，否则我割断你的喉咙！
Stay still or I'll cut your throat!
我没有自我介绍
I didn't introduce myself.
我是贝尔格莱德警察斯坦科 · 普莱蒂科西奇
Stanko Pletikosich, Belgrade police.
巴尔干半岛的阴影 第二季 第二集
BLACK SUN SEASON 2 EPISODE 2
好的，我一小时后再打给你
Yeah. I'll call you back in an hour.
不，这不是问题
No, it won't be a problem.
好吧，好的
Okay. Yes.
- 下午好 - 下午好
- Good afternoon. - Good afternoon.
我叫妮娜
My name is Nina.
你是来见彼得鲁塞夫斯基教授的吗？
You're here to see Professor Petrusevski?
- 是的 - 我是丹妮卡很高兴见到你
- Yes. - I'm Danica, nice to meet you.
这是我们在这所大学的新研究中心
This is our new research centre at the university.
它有八个亭子和一些辅助建筑
It has eight pavilions and, along with auxiliary buildings
它是欧洲这个地区最大的研究所之一
it's one of the largest in this part of Europe.
为什么它离城市这么远？
Why is it so far from the city?
因为这是一种优势
Because it's an advantage.
综合大楼只能通过预约或者许可进入
The complex is entered only by appointment or permission.
非常适合我们的工作
Ideal for our work.
他在等你
He's waiting for you.
好了，上楼梯，直走
There you go. Just go up the stairs, straight.
谢谢
Thanks.
亲爱的穆斯塔法，这是什么? ！
Dear Mujica, what's this?!
望远镜
Telescope.
不要跟我感情用事
Don't get me sentimentally.
你怎么可以在你把法国人送去他该去的地方之前
How is it possible that you didn't ask that Frenchman anything
什么都没问？
before you sent him to where he belongs?
问问你的那些人
Ask those people of yours.
米卡做了她的工作，他们后来对他做了什么..
Minka did her job. What did they do to him afterwards...
问问他们
Ask them.
我会惩罚他们
I'm gonna kick their asses.
- 你呢，米卡? - 什么？
- And you, Minka? - What?
我怎么了，穆斯塔法？
What's with me, Mustapha?
你为什么这么沮丧？
Why are you dispirited?
你最好给我做一些炒蛋
You better make me your scrambled eggs.
加油！特纳瓦茨！
Come on, Trnavatz!
加油！你的力量哪去了，你的青春哪去了? ！
Come on! Where's your strength, where's your youth?!
铲子的把手太短了
The handle of the shovel is short.
你的脑干也很短
Your mind is short.
特纳瓦茨，过来亲爱的！
Trnavatz! Come here, honey!
好吧，大家都无所事事
Well, yeah. Everyone is doing nothing,
所有的工作都是我在做
and I'm doing all the work.
你看到德拉吉尼亚了吗? 好像现在是1915年的
Did you see our Draginya? As if we are in 1915.
她应该去当国防部长
She should be Minister of Defence.
我们最终会陷入一场战争
We would end up in a war.
拿着这些钱
Take this money.
- 为什么? - 路上用
- Why? - For the road.
你要去趟马其顿
You're going to Macedonia.
这么大的雪我怎么走？
How should I go in this snow?
你知道保加利亚会发生什么吗？
You know what's gonna happen in Bulgaria?
狼群会吃了我
Wolves are going to eat me,
等到春天才会找到我的骨头
and you'll find my bones in spring, when the snow melts.
这总比被蒙克的雇佣兵杀死要好
That's better than being killed by Monk's mercenaries.
他们可以去死了
They can suck my dick.
去吧，去马其顿路上叨叨
Come on, start that shit of yours and go to Macedonia.
如果我不回来，就给我点根蜡烛
Light a candle for me if I don't come back.
特纳瓦茨！
Trnavatz!
德拉基尼亚，你怎么说？
Draginya, what do you say?
就像1915年塞尔维亚人徒步穿越阿尔巴尼亚
It's like 1915, when Serbs were crossing Albania on foot,
只是没有阿诺特在后面追杀我们
just without Arnauts to kill us.
有些人在贝尔格莱德
There are some of them in Belgrade,
把人们的头砍下来，你已经处理好了
to cut our heads off, you took care of that.
别这么说，德拉基尼亚
Don't say that, Draginya.
这倒是真的
Well, it's true.
你们没有一个人屈服，穷人都会死掉
None of you will give in, and the poor will die.
就像1915年一样
Just like in 1915.
孩子，你昨晚表现不错，你打得很好
Sonny, you were good last night. You fought well.
他没有打“好”，他把那个大块头干翻了
He didn't fight "well", he knocked the bighead's ass.
这是给你的钱
Here's some money for you.
带女孩出去吃蛋糕
To take the girl out, on a cake.
谢谢你，米兰！
Thank you, Milan!
- 妈妈拿着 - 什么！
- Mum, take this! - What?!
把钱还给我! 他挣来的! 还给我！
Give the money back! He earned it! Give it back!
你要教我怎么教育我的儿子吗？
Are you gonna teach me how to raise my son?
你自己生一个自己教育
Make your own and raise him then.
我曾经有过自己的儿子
I used to have my own son.
我有过儿子，但是..
I had my son but...
亲爱的上帝带走了他
Dear Lord took him.
他和...
He followed...
他和他的母亲
He followed his mother.
让我吻你
Let me kiss you.
怎么了？
Come on! What's wrong?
你为什么哭? 过来
Why are you crying? Come here.
对不起，米兰，我们生活在困难时期
Sorry, Milan. We live in difficult times.
狼藏在狗群中，周围有许多坏人
The wolves hid among the dogs, many bad people are around.
这很难
It's hard.
独自抚养他很难
It's hard to raise him alone.
我知道这很难，但是不要为他担心
I know it's hard but don't be afraid for him.
他不会有事的，对吧！
Nothing can happen to him, right?!
没错，米兰！
That's right, Milan!
你知道，孩子们长大了，就会走上自己的路
You know, kids grow up and go their own way.
我不为他担心
I'm not afraid for him.
我毫不怀疑是你教他找到正确的道路
I have no doubt you taught him to find the right path.
他是个好孩子！
He's a very good boy!
谢谢
Thanks.
你把他们关进监狱了吗？
Did you put them in prison?
如栅煮了咖啡，大家都想见你
Ruzha made coffee, everyone in Glavnjacha would like to see you.
不可能，我再也不会去那里了
No way, I would never go there again.
不过那是个不错的热身
That was a good warm up, though.
你错过了一些行动，是吗？
You miss some action, huh?
我受够了
I have enough of it.
但我有段时间没有逮捕任何人了
But I haven't arrested anyone in a while.
我们去休息下吧
Let's get some sleep.
你有没有听说日尔诺夫发生了一起谋杀案？
Have you heard there was a murder on Zhrnov?
我听说他们要拆毁日尔诺夫
I've heard they're tearing Zhrnov down.
没错，但是一个矿工被杀了
That is true, but a miner was killed,
军队把谋杀归咎于一个无关的穷人
and military service blamed some poor man for the murder.
这并不奇怪
Not surprised.
那个人渣维多杰，甚至会逮捕他的母亲
That shit, Vidoje, would arrest even his mother,
这样佩特拉和乔洛维奇就不会骂他了
just so that Pera and Djolovich wouldn't scold him.
谢谢
Thanks.
所以你什么都知道，你只是假装不知道
So, you know everything, you're just pretending not to.
我只管我自己的事
I'm minding my own business.
你要让一个无辜的人受苦？
You will let an innocent man suffer?
如果是维多杰说了算，那我也帮不了他了
If it was up to Vidoje, I wouldn't be able to help him,
但现在你已经介入了
but now that you have intervened
我知道你一定能坚持到底，就像我教你的那样
I know that you will finish it to the end, as I taught you.
不管怎样，我在那里都找不到什么
Either way, I have nothing to look for there.
塔尼，你得帮帮我！
Tane, you have to help me!
他们打断了我的调查，现在禁止进入
They interrupted my investigation, and now access to it is forbidden.
我才不管什么日尔诺夫！
I don't care about Zhrnov!
有一篇关于日尔诺夫的文章
There is a passage on Zhrnov
他的出口直接通向无名英雄的坟墓
whose exit leads straight to the grave of an unknown hero.
如果有出口，那就一定有入口
If there is an exit, there must be an entrance.
我必须回去找到那个入口
I must go back to find that entrance.
那你自己去找，跟我说这些干什么？
Do it, why do you need me?!
你对阿瓦拉了如指掌
You know Avala like the back of your hand.
是有一些隧道
There are some tunnels,
古罗马时期遗留下来的
left over from the time of the ancient Roman mines.
阿尔忒弥耶神父告诉过我
Father Artemiye told me about it.
也许就是这样
Maybe that's it.
请帮帮我
Help me, please.
你要知道，这是我最后一次帮你了
Just so you know, this is the last time I'm doing this.
这里真不错
It's nice here.
那个带我来这里的女孩
And the girl who brought me here,
是你的临时女友吗？
is that one of your casual girlfriends?
别傻了
Don't be silly.
丹妮卡是一位教授，也是一位同志
Danica is a professor and a comrade.
她把我们的牢房放在这里
She keeps our cell here.
我知道你是怎么和同志们一起工作的
I know how you work with comrades.
这地方干净得很，我看得出来
This place is clean as a whistle, as I can see.
如果你做其他类似的事情
If you do other things like this,
你不会有事的，亲爱的
you will be left alone, my dear.
如果我没记错的话，你以前没有抱怨过
If I remember correctly, you haven't complained before.
抱怨？
Complained?
谁会抱怨一个让自己睁开眼睛的孤儿
Who would complain about an orphan who came to get his eyes opened.
- 食物准备好了 - 亲爱的上帝
- The food is ready. - Dear Lord.
你以前是个辣妹
You used to be a hot chick.
- 我现在不是了？- 你是
- I'm not anymore?! - You are.
就这些吗？
Is this all?
真的？真不敢相信
Really?! Can't believe this.
我的老板有了一个新搭档
My boss has a new partner.
- 什么搭档？- 走私犯
- What partner? - A smuggler.
乌斯塔沙
The Ustasha.
他为美国黑手党工作，乔洛维奇带他来的
He works for the American mafia, Djolovich brought him.
军方带来了乌斯塔沙，而你现在才告诉我？
The service brought the Ustasha, and you're just telling me now?
如果我5分钟前告诉你
And if I had told you five mins ago,
一切都会不同吗！
everything would be different?!
- 你还知道什么? - 他叫安特
- What else do you know? - His name is Ante.
姓是..
Last name is...
我想不起来了... 戈迪纳！
I don't know... Godina!
你在开玩笑吗? 你还知道什么？
Are you kidding me? What else do you know?
我什么都不知道！
I don't know anything else!
看在上帝的份上，快去调查清楚！
Then go and find out, for God's sake!
下次你需要知道一切！
Next time you need to know everything!
好了，别对我吼了！
Okay, stop yelling at me!
- 反正我赶时间 - 你为什么赶时间？
- I'm in a hurry, anyway. - Why are you in a hurry?
你找到男朋友了吗？
Have you found a boyfriend?
我当然不会等你
I certainly won't wait for you.
醒醒吧
To come to your senses.
我是认真地问你
I'm seriously asking you.
是啊，我这个年纪也没什么好干的
Yeah, right, I have nothing better to do in this age.
- 艾米娜！- 什么事？
- Emina! - Yes?
你想念我们从斯托拉茨带来的樱桃吗？
Do you ever miss our cherries from Stolac?
不要跟我感情用事
Don't get me sentimentally.
你这个邪恶的变态！
You evil pervert!
你不和我一起去吗？
Won't you come with me?
不去
No.
帕皮在等你，我一会儿过去
Papi is waiting for you. I'll come later.
谁来签合同？
And who will sign the contract?
帕皮会检查所有的文件
Papi will check all the papers.
如果一切顺利，我会签字
If all goes well, I will sign.
好吧
All right.
但是我保证会带着一份签好的合同回去
But I promised to come back with a signed contract.
他们会失望的
They will be disappointed.
你昨晚的表现是不是也很奇怪？
Wasn't that weird for your last night too?
什么意思？
What you mean?
那个诺维奇？
On that Nowicki?
什么很奇怪？
What was weird?
我不知道
I do not know.
也许我对伯爵的想象不同
Maybe I imagined the count differently.
我希望我们今晚就能签合同
I wish we could sign the contract tonight.
亲爱的，我们最后一次做爱是什么时候？
Darling, when was the last time we had sex?
让我们先把工作做完，一切都会和以前一样
Let's get the job done first, and everything will be as before.
真的吗？克劳斯？
Really, Klaus?
塔宁，如果有人告诉我我会在教堂见到你
Well, Tane, if someone told me I'd see you at church,
我会觉得他疯了
I'd think he's crazy.
- 人是会变的，神父 - 谢天谢地
- People change, Father. - Thank God.
不要相信他，没有人能改变那么多
Don't trust him. Nobody has changed that much.
没关系，他还年轻！
It's okay. He's young!
你认识我的同事
You know my colleague.
我在帮他的忙，他对日尔诺夫很感兴趣
I'm helping him a bit, he's interested in Zhrnov.
你知道很多
And you know a lot about it.
确实
I do.
他们要拆了，是不是？
They're tearing it down, aren't they?
拆了挺好
I'm not sure how good that is.
等等，那里发生的谋杀案...
Wait, this murder that happened there...
你真的认为是拉杰科干的？
Do you really think that our Rajko did it?
调查将会确定这一点
The investigation will determine that.
当然，但是拉杰科真的是个好人
Of course. But Rajko is a really good man.
在教堂里对我帮助很大，曾经的战士
Helps me a lot here in the church. Former warrior.
他为这个国家而战
He fought for this country.
我是说他有他的缺点...
I mean, he has his flaws and...
他做什么事都靠自己
He does everything on his own hook.
但我不相信他会杀人
But I don't believe he would kill anyone.
我看见在那个无名英雄纪念碑附近有一条隧道
I saw a tunnel near the monument to the unknown hero.
我不知道入口在哪里
I wonder where the entrance is.
很多隧道都通往日尔诺夫
Many tunnels lead to Zhrnov.
那曾经是罗马时代的矿井
Those used to be mining shafts. In Roman times.
现在大多都被掩埋了
Now they are mostly buried,
有些村民把隧道当作食品储藏室
and some of them villagers use as a pantry.
从这出去就有一个入口
There is one entrance just when you get out of here,
应该是直通纪念碑的
which should lead straight to the monument.
那里真的埋了一个孩子吗？
Is it true that a child was buried there?
我不知道
I don't know.
挖掘工作于1921年完成
The exhumation was done in 1921.
差不多
It's possible.
许多人在这里被杀害
Many people were killed here.
在那个年代，人们找不到家人的尸体
In those years, families looked for their loved ones
就把他们的名字写在十字架上
in order to put at least their name on the cross.
神父，你能查出是谁被埋在那里吗？
Father, could you get information on who was buried there?
好久不见，亲爱的女士
Long time no see, dear lady.
是的
Yes.
在我看来，我们好像没有在俱乐部见过面
It seems to me that we haven't seen each other at the club.
没错
That's correct.
你想她吗？
Do you miss her?
已经无法改变
Nothing can be changed.
但是并没有从中吸取教训
But instead of learning something from that situation,
你还在自找麻烦
you are still looking for trouble.
你不是吗？
And you are not?
这是我的工作
That's my job.
谁说不是我的？
And who says it's not mine, too?
那你就是做错了
Then you're doing it wrong.
你做得很完美? 你不是在拿生命开玩笑？
And you're doing it perfectly? You're not playing with lives?
如果我没有假装不认识你呢？
What if I hadn't pretended not to know you?
如果... 但什么都没发生
What if... But nothing happened.
那你欠我一个解释
Then you owe me an explanation.
为什么共产国际突然对我们的组织感兴趣？
How come the Comintern is suddenly interested in our organization?
共产国际对什么都感兴趣
The Comintern is interested in everything.
尤其是你那个疯狂的组织
Especially since your crazy organization
一直在和法国人私下讨论
has been whispering to the French
如何在贝尔格莱德杀死亚历山大国王
on how to kill King Alexander in the middle of Belgrade.
什么? ! 他们想杀谁? ！
What?! Who do they want to kill?!
你真的什么都不知道？
You really don't know anything?
他们没告诉你是什么信息吗？
They didn't tell you what's in the message?
什么暗杀国王? ! 你在说什么？
What assassination of the king?! What are you talking about?
这就是我来问你的
That's what I came to ask you.
我? ! 我和这事没关系！
Me?! I have nothing to do with it!
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
你们的人民一直在推动这个国家
Your people have been pushing the country
投入德国的怀抱
into the arms of Germany for some time.
拜托，刺杀国王
Oh, come on! The assassination of the king
不可能对我有利！
can't be in my interest!
如果是这样，那么我们有共同的利益
If so, then we have common interests.
此时此刻
At the moment.
我会在贝尔格莱德中部亲自评判他
I would personally judge him in the middle of Belgrade.
但我有其他的安排
But I have a different order.
我不相信你，你在虚张声势
I don't believe you. You're bluffing.
但我相信你
But I do believe you.
你最好别让我失望
And you better not let me down.
或许你最好询问一下
Maybe you better inquire a little.
也许你会发现些什么
Maybe you'll find out something.
诺维奇除了要在贝尔格莱德会见亚历山大国王
That Nowicki, apart from King Alexander in Belgrade,
他应该也见了其他人
he was supposed to meet someone else.
显然是和你的组织有关的人
Apparently, with someone from your organization.
你就是这样找到我的
This is how you will find me.
波多黎各朗姆酒？
Puerto Rican rum?
没错
Exactly.
南斯拉夫王国 贝尔格莱德 保罗王子的住所
THE RESIDENCE OF PRINCE PAUL BELGRADE, KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
殿下...
Your Highness...
将军，你喜欢法国印象派画家吗？
General, do you like the French impressionists?
我更喜欢表现派画家
I prefer expressionists.
我邀请你来是要感谢你
I invited you to thank you for the services
在运送这些杰作的过程中提供的服务
you provided during the transport of these masterpieces.
我很荣幸能为您服务
I'm honoured to be of service.
至少像个警察一样，在我不是很好的时候
At least like a cop, when I'm not for the better.
说到法国白兰地！
Speaking of the French - cognac!
谢谢
Thanks.
那个法国外交官诺维奇伯爵
That French diplomat, Count Nowicki,
你可能知道他
you probably know that he didn't come
没有去会见王子殿下
to the meeting with His Royal Highness.
据我所知，他的一切痕迹都消失了
As I hear, every trace of him is lost.
我们正在加紧调查
We are working on it intensively,
但他好像消失得无影无踪，没人看见他
but it's like he vanished into thin air. Nobody saw him.
是的，但你确实见过他，不是吗？
Yes, but you did see him. Didn't you?
是的，陛下
I did, Your Majesty.
我能知道是为什么吗？
May I know why?
作为皇家卫队的首领
I thought it was unnatural that I,
对一位来自第五局的重要法国官员
as the head of the Royal Guard,
与国王的会面一无所知
knew nothing about the visit of such an important French official
我认为是不正常的
of the Fifth Bureau, to our king.
诺维奇伯爵是前来安排
Count Nowicki came to arrange the visit
法国外交部长巴尔图的来访
of the French Minister of Foreign Affairs, Bartu.
这是一项非常微妙的外交任务
This is a very delicate diplomatic task.
你的意思是南斯拉夫可能会承认
Do you mean the possible recognition
苏联的主权吗？
of the Soviet Union by Yugoslavia?
你不喜欢吗，将军？
And you don't like it, General?
任何一个认真负责的人都不会喜欢的
Any serious and responsible man wouldn't like it.
日瓦科维奇先生，我们生活在一个黑暗的时代
Mr. Zhivkovich, we live in murky times.
事物之间的联系迅速而不自然
Things connect quickly and unnaturally
很难判断谁是认真负责的
and it's difficult to assess who is serious and responsible.
调查清楚诺维奇先生到底怎么了
Try to find out what happened to Mr. Nowicki.
把你调查到的每一个细节
And I think it would be helpful if I was the first to be informed
都第一时间向我汇报
of all your essential steps.
我希望我们能互相理解
I hope we understood each other.
当然
Of course.
无价之宝
Priceless.
哦，操！
Oh, fuck!
- 怎么了? - 手电筒快把我折磨死了
- What's wrong? - The flashlight is killing me.
你怎么了? 你没事吧？
What's wrong with you? Are you okay?
在这种幽闭空间，我就会呼吸困难
Whenever I find myself indoors, I breathe a little harder.
你能继续吗？
Can you continue?
你先走
You go first.
- 就在这儿 - 哪儿? ！
- It was here. - Where?!
在这些石头上，我肯定它之前就在这里！
On these stones. I'm sure it was here!
你还问我为什么戒酒？
And you asked why I stopped drinking.
塔妮，我没疯！
Tane, I'm not crazy!
纪念碑在哪边？
Where do you go to the monument?
这边
This way.
- 然后怎么走？ - 这边
- Now where? - This way.
什么，你还没走？
What, you haven't left yet?
你要赶不上火车了
You'll be late for the train.
我们还在谈
We're still talking.
让我理清楚，亲爱的克劳斯
As far as I understand, dear Klaus,
你想再买一个铅矿对吗？
you would like to buy a lead mine? Again?
没错，是的
That's right, yes.
如果可以的话，我想问问为什么？
If I may ask, why?
简单地说，目前的市场状况告诉我
Simply, the current situation on the market tells me
在接下来的一段时间
that demand for raw materials
原材料的需求会急剧增加
will increase sharply in the following period.
人们应该抓住时机
One should seize the moment.
我想说的是你的观察
I would say your observations
都是基于政治形势
are based on the political situation,
而不是市场形势？
rather than the market one?
凡尔赛条约
Treaty of Versailles.
我们在数最后的日子，不是吗？
We're counting its last days, aren't we?
也许，是的
Maybe, yes.
- 我明白你的逻辑 - 然后呢？
- I understand your logic. - And?
亲爱的，你要迟到了
Honey, you'll be late.
等你回来我们再谈这个
Let's talk about this when you come back.
你总是对的，也许你还是应该跟我一起去？
You are right, as always. Maybe you should go after all?
你知道我不能
You know I can't.
我会尽快回来
I'll hurry.
再见
Good bye.
怎么面色凝重？
Why such a face?
我只是害怕
I'm just afraid
我们太急于进行新的投资
we're in too much of a hurry for a new investment.
帕皮，拜托，我还有很多其他的问题
Papi, please. I have plenty of other problems.
到目前为止，他一分钱也没付
He hasn't paid anything so far.
没什么
Nothing.
他让我们进入一个新的投资领域
And he makes us enter into a new investment.
这项重大投资将使我们破产
This major investment will make us insolvent.
并且如果他不按时付款
And if he doesn't pay on time,
他的期望没有实现
and his expectations aren't met,
我们的银行将会危在旦夕
the survival of our bank is at stake.
在另行通知之前停止一切投资
Stop it until further notice,
我去问问他到底是怎么回事
and I'll check with him on what it's all about.
我能问你个问题吗？
Can I ask you something?
你爱他吗？
Do you love him?
帕皮
Papi...
恐怕我所有的努力
I am afraid that all my efforts,
我所有与德国人联盟
all my investments,
进行的投资
that great alliance with the Germans,
所有的一切都会毁于一旦
all of it will go to hell.
和克劳斯 · 海涅曼一起
Altogether with Klaus Heinemann.
如果是这样，亲爱的
If so, my dear,
那我们必须快速做出反应
then we must react quickly.
给我派个人，要他带封信到镇上去
Send me a guy. He needs to take a letter to the town.
谢谢你照顾我
Thank you for taking care of me.
这里什么都没有！
There's nothing in here!
好了，孩子们! 休息时间结束了，回去工作吧！
All right, boys! The break is over, let's get back to work!
快点！
Come on!
快点，伙计们！
Come on, boys!
拿着这些铁锹
Take these shovels.
你们两个在这边，另外两个去那边，快点！
Two of you there, and the other two there. Come on!
怎么了？
What's wrong?
- 我没事，我没事 - 加油！
- I'm fine, I'm fine. - Come on!
塔尼！塔尼！
Tane! Tane!
怎么了？
What?!
快！
Come on!
- 等等，帽子 - 去他妈的帽子！
- Wait, the hat. - Oh, fuck the hat!
抓住我的手! 抓住！
Hold my hand! Hand!
- 该死！ - 快点！
- Damn it! - Come on!
- 坚持住，我们快到了 - 好，我没事
- Come on, we're almost there. - Okay, I'm fine.
探长，你真不是当矿工的料
Inspector, you're not meant to be a miner.
地面比较适合你
Stick to the surface.
你在下面看到过我说的东西吗？
Did you see the same thing in the crypt as I did?
- 你是说，什么都没有? - 是的
- You mean, nothing? - Yes.
你需要再和那个拉杰科谈谈
You need to talk to that Rajko again.
真要命！
Goddammit!
据我所知，阁下
As far as I understand, Excellency,
灵感来自亚述人的墓地
the inspiration is the Assyrian necropolis.
波斯统治者赛勒斯的古墓
Ancient tomb of the Persian ruler Cyrus.
还有这些女像柱？
And these caryatids?
它们分别代表一个南斯拉夫国籍
Each of them represents one nationality in Yugoslavia.
不是所有国籍的人都为南斯拉夫而战
Well, not all nationalities fought for Yugoslavia.
如果我们一直沉湎过去
If we keep going back to the past,
将毫无进展，先生
there is no progress for us, sir.
没错，萨夫科维奇先生
That's right, Mr. Savkovich.
我想感谢你的论文
I want to thank you for the support
为我们的项目提供的支持
your paper provides to our project.
为您效劳
At your service.
要是这种支持能够
If only that support would be transferred
转移给王子殿下的政府就好了
to the government of His Royal Highness.
我们只是公众的声音
We are just the voice of the public
只传播和解释公众的想法
and we only transmit and interpret what that public thinks.
我相信王子会理解的
I'm sure the prince understands that.
现代国家就是这么做的
This is how modern states do it.
比如德国
Germany, for example.
是的，德国也是如此
Among others, yes. Germany, too.
阁下！
Your Excellency!
我想我们应该私下谈谈
I thought we'd talk in private.
我觉得委员会的人都可以参与
I felt free to invite the whole committee for building the monument.
我希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind.
这会很有趣的
This is going to be fun.
王子殿下，我在想...
Mr. Prince, you know, I was thinking...
在这种情况下，我打算离开这个项目
Under these conditions, I intend to leave this project.
我要的大理石已经迟到三个星期了！三个星期！
My marble has been late for three weeks. Three!
所有的预算都用光了
All the budgets have been broken long ago,
现在又发生了一起谋杀案
and now some kind of murder has taken place.
这个问题立刻得到了解决
Which was resolved immediately.
毕竟，你们邀请我为一位默默无闻的英雄立一座纪念碑
After all, you invited me to make a monument to an unknown hero.
不是吗？
Didn't you?
现在却连尸骨都没有
There are no bones from either the known or the unknown.
你听说过吗？
Have you heard of it?
给我找到那个英雄！
Find me that hero!
有人把棺材从地窖里拿走了
Someone removed the bones from the crypt,
但我们迟早会找到的，我向你保证
but we will find them sooner or later, I guarantee you that.
梅斯特罗维奇先生，我们会调查你刚才所说的一切
Mr. Mestrovic, we will examine all the things you are talking about.
至于尸骨，阿瓦拉到处都是
And as for the bones, Avala is full of them.
那些保卫这个城市，这个国家的人们的遗骨
These are the bones of those who defended this city, this country.
所以别担心，会找到你的英雄的
So don't worry, you will have your hero.
我喜欢
I like it.
你好
Hello.
晚上好
Good evening.
嘿！
Hey!
- 你还在工作吗? - 是的
- Are you still at work? - I am.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem.
我们得再审问一下疯子拉杰科
We'll have to interrogate crazy Rajko again.
我不知道那个疯子还能告诉我们什么
I don't know what else that lunatic has to tell us.
例如，遗骸在哪里
Where are the remains, for example.
棺材从那个无名英雄的坟墓里消失了
They disappeared from the grave of that unknown hero.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
塔尼带我去了日尔诺夫
Tane took me to Zhrnov.
- 塔尼? 前探长? - 是的
- Tane? Former inspector? - Yes.
我不知道你们还会见面
I didn't know you're seeing each other.
你认为是拉杰科拿走的？
You think Rajko took them?
我不知道，所以我才要审问他
I don't know, that's why I have to question him.
拉杰克! 我们去了坟墓
Rajko! We went to the grave.
谁的？
Whose?
我的？
Mine?
快点，站起来！
Come on, stand up!
- 你听到了吗？- 等等
- Do you hear me?! - Wait, wait.
我们去了坟墓...
We went to the tomb and...
里面什么都没有
there's nothing in there.
没有
There isn't.
那里非常空虚
There is a lot of emptiness there.
里面甚至没有悲伤
There is not even sadness in there.
有人偷走了骸骨？
Someone stole the remains?
他不在那儿
He's not there.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
因为他...
Because he was...
根本就没有埋在那里
never buried there.
先生们，我有种预感
Gentlemen, I have a good spur.
什么预感，梅斯特罗维奇先生？
What do you have, Mr. Mestrovic?
- 那种感觉，维多杰 - 哦
- The feeling, Vidoje. - Oh.
我有预感我会赢某个人，那个人就是你
I have a feeling I'll beat someone tonight, and it's going to be you.
哦，真的吗? 我们走着瞧
Oh, really? We'll see about that.
萨夫科维奇先生，请来一下
Mr. Savkovich, please.
失陪一下，兰卡，倒酒
Excuse us, for a moment. Ranka, serve some drinks.
我不想喝酒
I don't want a drink.
这是干什么? 我们还玩吗? 天啊
What's this? Are we gonna play? Jesus.
真的很紧急
It's really urgent.
我们现在不谈生意
We won't talk business now.
我只是想问一下我什么时候能拿到钱
I just want to ask when I will be paid.
当时机成熟时
When the time comes.
我只剩下时间了
Time is what I have the least.
就像钱一样，我明白了
Just like money, I see.
如果你需要钱给你儿子，我会给他的
If you need it for your son, I'll give it to him.
我不想你给他钱
I don't want you to give him money.
但是请付钱给法官，他欠我很多钱
But please pay the judge, he owes me a lot of money.
等文件在法庭上证明无误后，他将获得赔偿
He will be paid when the document is certified in court.
我再也不能相信他了
I can't credit him anymore.
- 我不会的 - 那就不要
- And I won't. - Well, don't.
谁逼你了？
Who's forcing you?!
我们还玩吗？
Are we gonna play?
时间就是金钱，不是所有人都靠政府的薪水生活
Time is money. Not all of us live on a state salary
再加上腐败的收入，比如维多杰先生
combined with corrupt revenues, like Mr. Vidoje.
艺术家先生，你今天很能说，是吧？
Mr. State Artist, you are very open today, huh?
你激励了我，维多杰
You inspire me, Vidoje.
我们要开始了吗！
Are we going to start?!
没有你的牌
There are no cards for you.
为什么？
Why?
因为你欠我的
Because you owe me.
我还要跟你说多少遍？
How many times do I have to tell you the same?
离开房间
Leave the room.
等等，等等! 我只玩四人局
Wait, wait! I play only with four people.
那就别在这里玩
Then don't play here.
这是什么意思？
What's this?! What's this supposed to mean?
意思就是今晚没有牌局
It means there's no game tonight.
你知道出口在哪里
You know where the exit is.
这太过分了！
This is outrageous!
你在耍我们吗? ！
Are you fucking with us?!
没有
No.
那是兰卡的工作，但她今晚没心情
That's Ranka's job but she's not in the mood tonight.
先生们，我们回家吧，下周继续
Gentlemen, let's go home. We'll continue next week.
兰卡，你也回家吧，把钱退给他们
Ranka, that also applies to you, give people their money back.
请离开这个房间，你知道出口在哪里
Please, leave the room. You know where the exit is.
你留下！
You stay!
- 为什么？- 我想和你谈谈
- But why? - I want to talk to you.
- 他酿的白兰地？- 当然！
- His brandy? - Of course it's his!
- 闻起来像... - 山的味道！
- Oh, it's smells like... - Mountain!
什么山的味道? 闻起来像李子！
What fucking mountain? It smells like plum!
- 这是什么？- 血
- What's this? - Blood.
字母，所有的照片里都有
Letters. In all the photographs.
它倒吸一口新鲜空气！
It inhaled some fresh air!
你吸了什么东西! 所以你才胡说八道
You inhaled something else! That's why you talk nonsense.
- 什么？- 对，那也是血
- What? - Yeah, that's blood, too.
- 朱巴，坐下 - 不了，我赶时间
- Ljuba, take a seat. - No, I'm in a hurry.
普莱蒂科西奇督察说你可以留着这些照片
Inspector Pletikosich said that you can keep them.
谢谢
Thanks, Ljuba!
你的白兰地做得这么好，却不喝
You make such good brandy, and you don't drink it.
真遗憾
It is a pity.
这是什么，果汁？
What's this, a juice?
- 他真的杀了他 - 是的
- He really massacred him. - He did.
你说他的衣服上有泥土的痕迹？
You said there were traces of dust left on his clothes?
是的
Yes.
仿佛他们拖着他穿过了沼泽
As if they had dragged him through a swamp.
- 穿过隧道 - 穿过什么？
- Through a tunnel. - Through what?!
没什么
Never mind.
- 有几个人把他拉出来了 - 你怎么知道的？
- Several of them pulled him. - How do you know that?
从伤疤和刺伤的角度来看
From the angles at which the scars and stabs occurred.
你还注意到什么了吗？
Have you noticed anything else?
他前臂上有个纹身
He had a tattoo on his forearm,
他试图用刀刮掉，让它看起来像伤疤
which he tried to stab with a knife, to make it look like a scar,
下面有个十字架
and below that there's something like a cross.
- 东正教十字架？- 拜占庭十字架
- Orthodox cross? - Byzantine cross.
- 我们走！- 去哪儿？
- Let's go! - Where?
去停尸房
To the morgue.
我们为什么要去那里? ！
Why the fuck should we go there?!
看看尸体和纹身
To see the corpse and that tattoo.
你回警察局了吗？
Did you come back to the police?
没有，但我想看看这个
No, but I want to see this.
就像过去那些糟糕的日子一样! 普尔莎，帮我把这瓶白兰地打包！
Like the bad old days! Prsha, pack this brandy for me!
晚上好，博雅娜
Good evening, Boyana.
你来了
You're here.
我信守诺言
I keep my word.
你已经离开很久了
You've been gone for a long time.
我就是这样的人
That's how it is with me.
我想回瑞士
I wanted to go back to Switzerland.
然后去莫斯科
And go to Moscow.
你在那里找不到我
You wouldn't find me there.
我会的
I would...
我会找到你的
I would find you somewhere.
为了找到答案..
To find out...
什么答案？
What?
你是否还想要我
If you still want me.
我的宝贝
My babe.
我是你的，记住
I'm yours. Remember that.
明白吗？
Understand?
你保证会留在这里陪我
Promise you'll stay here with me.
我保证
I promise.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
等等！
Wait, wait, wait!
你想干什么？
What are you looking for? Huh?
等等！
Wait!
停停停！
Stop, stop, stop!
我们去你家吧
Let's go to your place.
奥地利 维也纳
VIENNA, AUSTRIA
我以为你也消失了
I thought you were gone too.
消失? 我为什么会消失？
I disappeared? Why would I disappear?
为什么人会消失？
Why do people disappear?
为了躲避某人
To avoid someone.
或者是因为有人想要让他消失
Or because someone wants to remove them.
我不明白你什么意思？
I don't understand, what you mean?
诺维奇得到了消息
Nowicki got the message.
你去了那里吗？
Have you been there?
是的，当然
Yes, of course.
真的吗？
Really?
你确定他没有在你不知情的情况下
Are you sure he didn't meet
单独与玛雅会面？
Maya without your knowledge?
是的，一切都按我们说好的那样进行
Yes. Everything went as we agreed.
不，不是的
No, it's not.
诺维奇消失得无影无踪
Nowicki disappeared without a trace.
想想
Think.
有什么不寻常的吗？
Was there anything unusual?
- 也许我... - 什么？
- Maybe, I... - What?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不知道伯爵为什么会消失
I didn't expect a count to behave like that.
现在怎么办？
And now what?
我们等着
We'll wait.
等什么？
For what?
等他重新出现
To reappear.
无论死活
Dead or alive.
幸好你离开了警察局，一切都完了
It's good you left the police, it's gone to hell.
我告诉主任: “给我一些新人
I told chief: "Give me some new people,
年轻，漂亮，愚蠢都行”
young, beautiful, stupid."
我老了，不能一个人在这里工作
I'm old, I can't work here alone.
但他不在乎
But he doesn't care.
你想喝点什么吗？
Would you like a drink?
不，该死，这里有很多尸体
No. Damn it, you have a lot of corpses here.
是的，确实有很多
Yeah, there are many of them.
在这儿! 巴雅克塔维奇，四号床
Here it is! Baryaktarevich, bed number four.
尸体在哪儿? ！
Where's the corpse?!
我也想知道
I would like to know that, too.
”我需要你——玛雅”
"I need you. Maya"